# Alence Abhinay Gopaldas

+1 437 428 8179 • 406 White Birch Ave • <u>alence311@gmail.com</u> • <u>www.alence.tech</u>

# **UI/UX Designer**

### **User Interface | User Experience | Design Innovation**

4 years of experience in UI & UX designing. I have experience collaborating with existing business and UX teams, creating prototypes, and synthesizing user feedback. My skillset consists of Figma and Adobe XD, which allow me to develop customer-centric solutions that meet the needs of a dynamic organization.

## **Key Skills**

UX Designing
UI Designing
Front-end programming
Graphic Designing
Prototyping
Wireframing
Illustration
3D & 2D Animation
Design Analysis
Website Design
JavaScript

### **TOOLS**

Figma
Adobe XD
Sketch
Adobe Photoshop
Adobe Illustrator
WordPress

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# **SRAK Prestek Pvt Ltd** - Hyderabad, IN

01/2023 - 04/2023

02/2016 -

11/2019 - PRESENT

#### **UI Designer**

- Translated client requirements into engaging interfaces using Figma and Adobe XD, achieving a 20% boost in user satisfaction.
- Established design consistency with UI patterns, fostering a unified brand identity and contributing to a 15% increase in user interaction and product effectiveness through usability testing and feedback-driven iterations.

**Capgemini Technology Services** - *Hyderabad, IN* 09/2018

#### **UX/UI Designer**

- Assisted senior designers in creating visually appealing marketing materials, such as brochures, posters, and digital graphics, resulting in a 20% increase in customer engagement and brand recognition.
- Demonstrated a strong understanding of brand guidelines, ensuring consistency in Design across 15+ projects and receiving positive client feedback on brand representation.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams, effectively gathering project requirements and delivering designs that met or exceeded client expectations, resulting in a 95% client satisfaction rate.
- Engaged in brainstorming for innovative design solutions, contributing creative input, and streamlined design processes. Developed user flows, wireframes, prototypes, and a style guide for project-wide consistency.

# **Key Responsibilities as a freelancer**-*Internationally* **UI Designer | UX Designer | Graphic Designer**

I have done various projects for multiple startup companies in developing Mobile & Web applications, including visuals, illustrations, videos, and other media.

 Produced compelling visual content for startups, ensuring brand consistency, and enhancing user engagement across various platforms while overseeing end-to-end projects and aiding clients in digital strategy and online presence.

#### **EDUCATION**

**Conestoga College -** *Ontario, CN* 

Graduation Diploma – Web Development, December 2023

Gokaraju Rangaraju Institute of Engineering and Technology (GRIET) - Hyderabad, IN

Bachelors of Technology (BE/B.tech) - ECE, November 2020

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

**PATENTS** - Hyderabad, IN

01/2019 - 10/2023

#### **Smart Pill box**

An automated electronic device for reminding consumption of pills scheduled and even for missed schedules with specified two-way confirmation along with replaceable pill compartments' layer as value addition been facilitated to the changing requirements of the care-taker or consumer as disclosed in the above-mentioned application for the term of 20 years from the 21st day of January 2019 in accordance with the provisions of the Patents Act,1970.

• Patent No.: 459986

• Application No.: 201941002559

• Date of Filing: 21/01/2019

Designed and developed pillbox:

• Adobe Illustrator for initial pill box design and used blender for 3D design.

• Used IoT concepts for developing the box functionality.

CONHACK2023 - Ontario, CN

10/2023

#### Secured 3rd place in Conestoga College's hackathon

- where over 100 participants formed 28 groups, working relentlessly for 8 hours.
- Developed and Designed frontend of the website, which converts audio into downloadable text transcripts.
- Tools: Adobe Illustrator, Adobe XD and VS code.

#### LANGUAGES

- English (Fluent: Speaking, Reading & Writing)
- Telugu (native) (Fluent: Speaking, Reading & Writing)
- Hindi (Fluent: Speaking, Reading & Writing)